[
  {
    "question": "Which is the most popular JavaScript framework?",
    "options": ["Angular", "React", "Svelte", "Vue"],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "What does HTML stand for?",
    "options": [
      "HyperText Makeup Language",
      "HyperText Markup Language",
      "High-Level Text Language",
      "HyperTransfer Markup Language"
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "What is CSS?",
    "options": [
      "Computer Style Sheets",
      "Cascading Style Sheets",
      "Centralized Style System",
      "EffecCreative Style Solutionsts"
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "What is JavaScript, and how does it differ from Java?",
    "options": [
      "JavaScript is a subset of Java.",
      "JavaScript is used for web interactivity; unrelated to Java",
      "Java is a scripting language like JavaScript.",
      "JavaScript and Java are synonymous."
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the concept of variable scope in JavaScript.",
    "options": [
      "Scope refers to the visibility of an element on a webpage.",
      "JavaScript has only global scope.",
      "Variable scope refers to the context in which variables are defined ",
      " Scope is irrelevant in JavaScript."
    ],
    "correctOption": 2,
    "points": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "Explain the difference between margin and padding in CSS.",
    "options": [
      "Margin is space inside an element; padding is space outside an element.",
      "Margin is space outside an element; padding is space inside an element ",
      "Margin and padding are the same.",
      "Margin and padding are used interchangeably."
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 10
  },
  {
    "question": "When to use derived state in React?",
    "options": [
      "Whenever the state should not trigger a re-render",
      "Whenever the state can be synchronized with an effect",
      "Whenever the state should be accessible to all components",
      "Whenever the state can be computed from another state variable"
    ],
    "correctOption": 3,
    "points": 30
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the difference between \"block\" and \"inline\" elements in HTML.",
    "options": [
      "Block elements take up as much width as necessary.",
      "Inline elements start on a new line",
      "Block elements don't start on a new line.",
      "Inline elements take up the full width available."
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 20
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the CSS box model and its components.",
    "options": [
      "Defines the shape of CSS elements.",
      "Consists of content only.",
      "Consists of content, padding, border, and margin",
      "Describes the layout of the webpage."
    ],
    "correctOption": 2,
    "points": 20
  },
  {
    "question": "How does asynchronous programming work in JavaScript, and what are callbacks?",
    "options": [
      "Asynchronous tasks are executed sequentially.",
      "Asynchronous tasks execute in parallel; callbacks are functions passed to another function and executed after an asynchronous operation",
      "Asynchronous programming is not supported in JavaScript",
      "Callbacks are used for synchronous operations only"
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 30
  },
  {
    "question": "How can you center an element horizontally and vertically in CSS?",
    "options": [
      "Use the \"center\" property.",
      "Apply \"margin: auto;\" for horizontal centering",
      "Set \"vertical-align: center;\"",
      "Use the \"center-align\" attribute."
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 20
  },
  {
    "question": "Describe the purpose of the \"this\" keyword in JavaScript.",
    "options": [
      "Refers to the current element in the DOM.",
      "\"this\" points to the next function in line.",
      "\"this\" refers to the current execution context",
      "\"this\" is a placeholder for undefined values."
    ],
    "correctOption": 2,
    "points": 30
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the significance of the \"alt\" attribute in an HTML image tag?",
    "options": [
      "Alternate image style",
      "Image alignment",
      "Alternative text for accessibility and if the image cannot be loaded ",
      "Altitude of the image"
    ],
    "correctOption": 2,
    "points": 30
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between \"class\" and \"id\" selectors in CSS?",
    "options": [
      "Classes can be used on multiple elements; IDs must be unique",
      "Classes must be unique; IDs can be used on multiple elements.",
      "Classes and IDs are interchangeable.",
      "Classes and IDs serve the same purpose."
    ],
    "correctOption": 0,
    "points": 30
  },
  {
    "question": "What is the difference between \"undefined\" and \"null\" in JavaScript?",
    "options": [
      "Both represent the absence of a value.",
      "\"undefined\" means a variable has been declared but not defined; \"null\" represents the absence of any object value",
      "\"undefined\" and \"null\" are interchangeable.",
      "\"undefined\" is used for objects; \"null\" is used for variables."
    ],
    "correctOption": 1,
    "points": 30
  }
]
